# Ciupei Calin



calinciupei@gmail.com

# Summary

Experienced 8+ years Senior Frontend Developer with a demonstrated history of working in different types of industry like entertainment, tourism, and commerce. During my working experience as a Front-end Developer, I have improved my proficiency with JS, CSS, and HTML. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing SPA by 80% with improved code design.

# **Experience**



#### Senior Frontend Developer

# Paddy Power Betfair

Jan 2020 - Present (1 year 10 months +)

Migrated a multi-page component into a single-page app using Typescript, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, improving customer engagement.

Improve and deliver new features in multiple components using tools like React, and Typescript Performed code reviews and bug fixes, reducing technical debt.

Deliver multiple dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, Javascript (React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Typescript)

Built extensive test coverage for all new features, reducing the number of customer complaints. Mentored and train junior front-end developers.

Worked with Nodejs tool and frameworks like Webpack, Babel, Grunt, Express, GraphQL to create Rest API's services from scratch or features to deliver the outcomes for different types o projects Experience writing unit tests using tools: Jest, Jasmine, assertion libraries Chai, Expect, and test runners like Karma.

#### Front End Developer

#### Paddy Power Betfair

Jun 2016 - Jan 2020 (3 years 8 months)

Deliver multiple dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, Javascript (YUI, React, Redux)

Migrated a multi-page component into a single-page app using Angular Js, Angular improving customer engagement.

Improve and deliver new features in multiple components using frameworks like YUI and React. Migrate multiple components to styling code by using methodologies like CSS BEM and OOCSS Worked with Nodejs tool and frameworks like Webpack, Babel, Grunt, Express, GraphQL to create Rest API's services from scratch or features to deliver the outcomes for different types o projects Experience writing unit tests using tools: Jest, Jasmine, assertion libraries Chai, Expect, and test runners like Karma.



#### Web Developer

**IN2ITIVE** 

Jul 2015 - Jun 2016 (1 year)

Coordination, analysis and tasks estimation received from customers.

Develope and implement applications according to the requirements and standards.

Analyse code and propose solutions to achieve maximum performance by the team.

Provide support to clients from initial client interaction and requirements analysis through design, coding, testing, debugging, implementation.



#### Webmaster

#### Cognizant Softvision

Oct 2014 - Jul 2015 (10 months)

Take an active role in the full development life-cycle.

Successfully build and maintain a variety of applications and produce documentation and reports.

Testing, identifying problems, report them using Jira as Project Management Tool.

Providing first level technical support.



# Web Developer

# Freelance PHP & Python & Node.js developers

Oct 2012 - Oct 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Maintaining and enhancing company software.

Maintaining web components and websites for both new and existing clients.

Testing site functionality, identifying problems or bugs and fixing errors.

Coding using front-end technologies, such as CSS, JavaScript and HTML.

Ensure site usability, SEO and browser compatibility.

Working on back-end technologies such as PHP using Aptana Studio 3 as integrated development environment.

Involved in front-end design, site maintenance & email marketing campaigns.



### Junior Test Engineer

#### Neusoft EDC

Dec 2011 - Aug 2012 (9 months)

Identification and reporting the bugs in bug tracking system;

Directing software compatibility tests with programs, hardware, operating systems, or network environments.

Functional testing of mobile applications on Windows platform.

Running test cases.

Reporting the found bugs.

#### **Education**



#### Technical University of Cluj Napoca

Master Of Computer Science, Master 2012 - 2014



# 🤊 Tehnical University of Cluj Napoca - Romania

Faculty of Electrical Engineering, Licensed 2004 - 2009

# **Licenses & Certifications**

- in Learning AngularJS 2 (2016) LinkedIn
- Improving Your Focus LinkedIn
- React VR: Interactive Multimedia LinkedIn
- in Learning Redux LinkedIn
- The Learning NgRx LinkedIn
- GraphQL: Data Fetching with Relay LinkedIn
- React (Basic) HackerRank d8d28990231a
- **LFW212: Node.js Services Development** The Linux Foundation

# **Skills**

Front-End Development • JavaScript • React.js • AngularJS • Angular • Node.js • GraphQL • jQuery • Redux.js • TypeScript